The identity operator, is, is used to see if two
variables are taking up the same memory space.
The identity operator is important when speed is
of utmost importance, as it is often in a game
situation. To demonstrate the identity operator,
I have this 145-identity file open. The code is
similar to the code in the 135-identity file.
The code contains colors and ranks for teams
used in a game. The same value is assigned to
teams 1 and 3 on lines 1 and 3. Team 2 is set
to be equal to Team 1, as the code indicates on
line 2. The two print statements on lines 5 and 6
use the is keyword to see if team1 and team2 use
the same memory space, which saves memory space
and can make an app run more efficiently, and if
team1 and team3 use the same memory space. I will
run this code, and we get one True result and one
False result. Team1 is Team2 because team2 did not
have a specific value assigned to it. Instead, it
took the value of team1, meaning it is a variable
that uses the value in team1’s memory space.
Conversely, team1 is not team3 because, even
though the value of team3 is the same as that of
team1, the value was explicitly assigned to team3,
giving team3 its own memory space. To further show
the difference between identity and comparison
operators, I will add a print statement to line 7
showing whether team1 equals team3. I will rerun
the code and value-wise, team1 and team3 have the
same values so that print statement returns true.